Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
欢迎回来
So, in this video and in this notebook,
在此视频和 notebook 中
I'll be showing you how to actually train neural networks in PyTorch.
我将演示如何在 PyTorch 里训练神经网络
So, previously, we saw how to define neural networks in PyTorch using the nn module,
之前我们学习了如何使用 nn 模块在 PyTorch 中定义神经网络
but now we're going to see how we actually take
现在我们将学习
one of these networks that we defined and train it.
如何训练网络
So, what I mean by training is that we're going to use
训练是指我们将使用
our neural networks as a universal function approximator.
神经网络作为通用函数逼近器
What that means is that,
也就是说
for basically any function,
对于任何函数
we have some desired input for example,
我们传入输入
an image of the number four,
例如图像 4
and then we have some desired output of this function.
然后获得函数输出
In this case a probability distribution that
在这个例子里 输出就是概率分布
is telling us the probabilities of the various digits.
告诉我们各个数字的概率
So, in this case,
在此例中
if we passed it in image four,
如果我们传入图像 4
we want to get out a probability distribution where there's
我们希望获得一个概率分布
a lot of probability in the digit four.
其中数字 4 的概率最高
So, the cool thing about neural networks is that if
神经网络的一个强大之处是
you use non-linear activations and then
如果使用非线性激活函数
you have the correct dataset of these images that are labeled with the correct ones,
我们传入带有正确标签的正确图像数据集
then basically you pass in an image and the correct output,
即传入一个图像、正确的输出、以及
the correct label or class,
正确的标签/类别
and eventually your neural network will build to approximate this function that is
最终 神经网络将能够逼近此函数
converting these images into this probability distribution, and that's our goal here.
将这些图像变成这个概率分布 这就是我们的目标
So, basically we want to see how in PyTorch,
也就是说 我们将学习
we can build a neural network and then we're going to give it the inputs and outputs,
在 PyTorch 中如何构建神经网络并提供输入和输出
and then adjust the weights of that network so that it approximates this function.
然后调整网络权重 使其逼近该函数
So, the first thing that we need for that is what is called a loss function.
首先我们需要一个损失函数
So, it's sometimes also called the cost,
有时候也称为成本函数
and what this is it's a measure of our prediction error.
它可以衡量预测错误
So, we pass in the image of a four and then
比如 我们传入图像 4
our network predicts something else that's an error.
网络预测为其他不正确的数字
So, we want to measure how far away our networks prediction is from the correct label,
损失函数就是为了评估
and we do that using loss function.
网络的错误预测与正确预测的偏差程度
So, in this case, it's the mean squared error.
这里我们使用均方误差
So, a lot of times you'll use this in regression problems,
回归问题中经常使用均方误差
but use other loss functions and classification problems like this one here.
但是在分类问题中使用其他损失函数 例如这个
So, the loss depends on
损失取决于
the output of our network or the predictions our network is making.
网络的输出或预测
The output of a network depends on the weight.
网络的输出取决于权重
So, like the network parameters.
即网络参数
So, we can actually adjust our weights such that this loss is minimized,
我们可以调整权重 使损失最小化
and once the loss is minimized,
最小化损失后
then we know that our network is making as good predictions as it can.
表明网络预测已尽可能达到最佳效果
So, this is the whole goal to adjust our network parameters to minimize our loss,
这就是整个目标 即调整网络参数以最小化损失
and we do this by using a process called gradient descent.
方法是使用梯度下降法
So, the gradient is the slope of the loss function with respect to our perimeters.
梯度是损失函数相对于参数的斜率
The gradient always points in the direction of fastest change.
梯度始终指向变化最快的方向
So, for example if you have a mountain,
以山峰为例
the gradient is going to always point up the mountain.
梯度将始终指向上山方向
So, you can imagine our loss function being like
假设这座山峰就是损失函数
this mountain where we have a high loss up here and we have a low loss down here.
上面是很高的损失 下面是很低的损失
So, we know that we want to get to the minimum of our loss when we minimize our loss,
我们希望达到最低损失
and so, we want to go downwards.
因此需要朝着下山方向移动
So, basically, the gradient points upwards and so,
梯度朝着向上的方向
we just go the opposite direction.
我们就沿着相反的方向移动
So, we go in the direction of the negative gradient,
即沿着负梯度方向
and then if we keep following this down,
如果不断向下移动
then eventually we get to the bottom of this mountain, the lowest loss.
最终会抵达这座山的最底部 即达到最低损失
With multilayered neural networks,
对于多层神经网络
we use an algorithm called backpropagation to do this.
我们将使用一种叫做反向传播的算法
Backpropagation is really just an application of the chain rule from calculus.
反向传播是微积分中的链式法则的一种应用
So, if you think about it when we pass in some data,
我们向网络中
some input into our network,
传入一些输入数据
it goes through this forward pass through the network to calculate our loss.
使数据在网络中前向传播 并计算损失
So, we pass in some data,
传入一些数据
some feature input x and then it goes through
即输入特征 x
this linear transformation which depends on our weights and biases,
经过这个线性转换 该转换取决于权重和偏差
and then through some activation function like a sigmoid,
然后经过激活函数 例如 S 型函数
through another linear transformation with some more weights and biases,
再经过具有其他权重和偏差的另一个线性转换
and then that goes in,
然后
from that we can calculate our loss.
计算损失
So, if we make a small change in our weights here, W1,
如果对这里的权重 w1 进行小小的改动
it's going to propagate through the network and
改动将在网络里传播
end up like results in a small change in our loss.
最终导致损失有小小的变化
So, you can think of this as a chain of changes.
可以将这个流程看做链式变化
So, if we change here, this is going to change.
如果更改这个 这个将改变
Even that's going to propagate through here,
变化传播到这里
it's going to propagate through here, it's going to propagate through here.
传播到这里 再传播到这里
So, with backpropagation, we actually use these same changes,
对于反向传播来说 我们将使用相同的变化
but we go in the opposite direction.
但是朝着相反的方向传播
So, for each of these operations like the loss and
对于每个操作
the linear transformation into the sigmoid activation function,
例如损失 线性转换 S 型激活函数
there's always going to be some derivative,
始终存在某个导数
some gradient between the outputs and inputs, and so,
在输出和输入之间存在梯度
what we do is we take each of the gradients for
我们对每个操作求导
these operations and we pass them backwards through the network.
然后使导数在网络里反向传播
Each step we multiply the incoming gradient with the gradient of the operation itself.
在每一步 我们将传入梯度乘以操作本身的梯度
So, for example just starting at the end with the loss.
从末尾（损失）开始
So, we pass this gradient or the loss dldL2.
传入这个梯度 即 ∂l/∂L2
So, this is the gradient of the loss with respect to the second linear transformation,
这是损失相对于第二个线性转换的梯度
and then we pass that backwards again and if we multiply it by the loss of this L2.
再次反向传播 使其乘以 L2 的损失
So, this is the linear transformation with respect to
这是线性转换相对于
the outputs of our activation function,
激活函数输出的导数
that gives us the gradient for this operation.
得出这个操作的梯度
If you multiply this gradient by the gradient coming from the loss,
将这个梯度乘以损失的梯度
then we get the total gradient for both of these parts,
得出这两个部分的总梯度
and this gradient can be passed back to this softmax function.
这个梯度可以往回传递给这个 softmax 函数
So, as the general process for backpropagation, we take our gradients,
这就是反向传播的一般流程
we pass it backwards to the previous operation,
我们将梯度反向传递给上一个操作
multiply it by the gradient there,
使其乘以这里的梯度
and then pass that total gradient backwards.
然后再反向传播总梯度
So, we just keep doing that through each of the operations in our network,
我们继续针对网络中的每个操作执行这一流程
and eventually we'll get back to our weights.
最终将回到权重部分
What this does is it allows us to calculate
使我们能够计算
the gradient of the loss with respect to these weights.
损失相对于这些权重的梯度
Like I was saying before,
正如我之前提到的
the gradient points in the direction of fastest change in our loss,
梯度指向损失变化最快的方向
so, to maximize it.
因此最大化它
So, if we want to minimize our loss,
如果要最小化损失
we can subtract the gradient off from our weights,
我们可以用权重减去梯度
and so, what this will do is it'll give us a new set of weights
这样会生成一组新的权重
that will in general result in a smaller loss.
使损失变得更小
So, the way that backpropagation algorithm works is that it will
反向传播算法的工作原理是
make a forward pass through a network, calculate the loss,
在网络中前向传播一次 计算损失
and then once we have the loss, we can go
获得损失后
backwards through our network and calculate the gradient,
我们可以在网络中反向传播并计算梯度
and get the gradient for a weights.
获得权重的梯度
Then we'll update the weights.
然后更新权重
Do another forward pass,
再次前向传播
calculate the loss, do another backward pass, update the weights,
计算损失 再次反向传播 更新权重
and so on and so on and so on,
不断重复
until we get sufficiently minimized loss.
直到损失足够小
So, once we have the gradient and like I was saying before,
获得梯度后
we can subtract it off from our weights,
我们可以用权重减去梯度
but we also use this term Alpha which is called the learning rate.
我们还在这里使用了 α 表示学习速率
This is basically just a way to scale our gradients so that we're not
学习速率可以用来调整梯度
taking too large steps in this iterative process.
确保在迭代过程中步长不会太大
So, what can happen if you're update steps are too large,
如果更新步长太大
you can bounce around in this trough around
可能会在最低值周围浮动
the minimum and never actually settle in the minimum of the loss.
但始终不会达到最低损失值
So, let's see how we can actually calculate losses in PyTorch.
我们来看看如何在 PyTorch 中计算损失
Again using the nn module,
同样使用 nn 模块
PyTorch provides us a lot of different losses including the cross-entropy loss.
PyTorch 提供了很多不同的损失 包括交叉熵损失
So, this loss is what we'll typically use when we're doing classification problems.
在分类问题中 我们通常使用这个损失
In PyTorch, the convention is to assign our loss to its variable criterion.
在 PyTorch 中 我们会将损失赋值给这个变量 criterion
So, if we wanted to use cross-entropy,
如果要使用交叉熵损失
we just say criterion equals nn.crossEntropyLoss and create that class.
直接输入 criterion = nn.CrossEntropyLoss 创建这个类
So, one thing to note is that,
需要注意的一点是
if you look at the documentation for cross-entropy loss,
打开交叉熵损失的文档会发现
you'll see that it actually wants the scores
交叉熵损失的输入
like the logits of our network as the input to the cross-entropy loss.
应该是网络分数/对数
So, you'll be using this with an output such as softmax,
所以 要使用 softmax 等输出
which gives us this nice probability distribution.
softmax 可以提供正常的概率分布
But for computational reasons,
但是出于计算原因
then it's generally better to use the logits which are
通常使用对数作为该损失函数的输入更合适
the input to the softmax function as the input to this loss.
对数是 softmax 函数的输入
So, the input is expected to be the scores
因此输入应该是每个类别的分数
for each class and not the probabilities themselves.
而不是概率本身
So, first I'm going to import the necessary modules
首先我将导入必要的模块
here and also download our data and create it in,
并下载数据
like you've seen before, as a trainloader,
然后创建 trainloader
and so, we can get our data out of here.
然后从中获取数据
So, here I'm defining a model.
我在这里定义一个模型
So, I'm using nn.Sequential, and if you haven't seen this,
我使用的是 nn.Sequential 如果你不熟悉这个函数
checkout the end of the previous notebook.
请参阅上个 notebook 的结尾内容
So, the end of part two,
Part 2 notebook 里
will show you how to use nn.Sequential.
将演示如何使用 nn.Sequential
It's just a somewhat more concise way to define simple feed-forward networks, and so,
它可以简洁地定义简单前馈网络
you'll notice here that I'm actually only returning the logits,
我在这里仅返回对数
the scores of our output function and not the softmax output itself.
即输出函数的分数 而不是 softmax 输出本身
Then here we can define our loss.
在这里定义损失
So, criterions equal to nn.crossEntropyLoss.
输入 criterions = nn.CrossEntropyLoss
We get our data with images and labels,
获取图像和标签数据
flatten it, pass it through our model to get the logits,
扁平化图像 传入模型中并获得对数
and then we can get the actual loss by bypassing in our logits and the true labels,
通过传入对数和真实标签获得实际损失
and so, again we get the labels from our trainloader.
同样 从 trainloader 中获取标签
So, if we do this, we see we have calculated the loss.
运行下代码 可以看出 我们计算出了损失
So, my experience, it's more convenient to build your model
使用 log-softmax 输出构建模型
using a log-softmax output instead of just normal softmax.
比使用普通的 softmax 更方便
So, with a log-softmax output to get the actual probabilities,
对于 log-softmax 输出 要获得实际概率
you just pass it through torch.exp. So, the exponential.
直接传入 torch.exp计算指数
With a log-softmax output,
对于 log-softmax 输出
you'll want to use the negative log-likelihood loss or nn.NLLLoss.
需要使用负对数似然损失或 nn.NLLLoss
So, what I want you to do here is build
下面你的任务是
a model that returns the log-softmax as the output,
构建一个模型并返回 log-softmax 作为输出
and calculate the loss using the negative log-likelihood loss.
使用负对数似然损失计算损失
When you're using log-softmax,
在使用 log-softmax 时
make sure you pay attention to the dim keyword argument.
要注意关键字参数 dim
You want to make sure you set it right so that the output is what you want.
确保正确设置该参数 才能获得符合期望的输出
So, go and try this and feel free to check out my solution.
试试吧
It's in the notebook and also in the next video,
如果遇到问题
if you're having problems. Cheers.
可以在 notebook 和下个视频中查看我的答案加油！